Jarod Sjogren

jarod.sjogren@uga.edu • (404)786-0701 Github: https://github.com/JSSjogren LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/jarodsjogren/ Website: http://jarodsjogren.com

PRESENT ADDRESS

260 Springdale Street Apt. #27 Athens, GA 30606 United States PERMANENT ADDRESS

1031 Jonathan Lane Tucker, Georgia 30084 United States

OBJECTIVE

As a goal-oriented and organized individual, I will add significant value to the Software Engineering Internship position at here at Blizzard. My strong sense of self motivation, prior work experience, and passion for videogames will ensure meaningful contributions to any project that I'm assigned to within the company.

EDUCATION

Honors Student at The University of Georgia, Athens, GA

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science, Expected Graduation May 2019

- Zell Miller Scholarship Recipient
- Current Overall GPA: 3.80/4.00
- Recipient of Deans List (Fall 2015, Spring 2017) and Presidential Scholar (Spring 2016)

TECHNICAL EXPERIENCE

Programming Languages: Java, C++, HTML (WIP), CSS (WIP), and Javascript (WIP)

Operating Systems: Windows 2000/ XP/ Vista/ 7/ 8/ 10, Unix (Linux/Red Hat/Ubuntu), macOS, iOS

Software: SFTP, SSH, Putty, Microsoft Products, Eclipse (C++ and Java), IntelliJ, Notepad++, Brackets, EMACS,

Ncurses, Xcode

CODING

Projects outside University:

- Created server-side plugin modifications for Minecraft (Can provide if requested)
- Developed plugins for and participated in leadership for select Minecraft servers
- Created client-side modifications for Minecraft (Can provide if requested)
- Developed a modified client for a customer to enhance their game experience
- Designed and coded bill splitter and rent/floor plan app for residents of Towne Club apartment complex
- Involved in development of the Warp the Word iOS application through the Association for Computing Machinery

Projects within University:

- Text Editor (C++ in NCurses)
- Unix Command Shell (C++, supported background processes and process management)
- MySQL Simulator (Java w/ Swing API)

CAMPUS & COMMUNITY INVOLVEMENT

Student Government Association Freshman Programs (Freshman Forum), September 2015 - May 2016

- Dedicated 3 hours each week to serving the community, and developing leadership skills.
- Built and fostered a community within the Student Government family to ensure that the inspiration to give continues on.
- Participated in planning and execution of service events throughout the Fall and Spring semesters.

Association for Computing Machinery (ACM), August 2017 - Present

 Active in multiple subsets of ACM focusing on app development, web development, and video game development.

Gwinnett Student Leadership Team, June 2013 - July 2015

GSLT is an elite program for select students in the Gwinnett county area, designed by Ms. Nancy Ward to instill a sense of leadership in the community. They meet monthly to hear from prominent speakers from around the country, who cover select topics from a rigorous curriculum. The program occurs from Junior year, through the end of Senior year, when the students graduate from high school.

WORK EXPERIENCE

$\begin{tabular}{ll} \textbf{Computing} & \textbf{and Digital Imaging Sales Consultant}, & \textbf{Best Buy}, & \textbf{Athens}, & \textbf{GA} \\ \end{tabular}$

BestBuy.com

Sales Consultant, June 2017 - October 2017

- Engage customers using selling skills to build complex, connected solutions in a fast-paced, dynamic environment where customers feel supported and leave delighted.
- Inspire customers by showing them whats possible with technology.
- Use innovative training tools to stay current, confident and complete, driving profitable growth and achieving individual and department goals.
- Accumulate and apply the appropriate knowledge and expertise through continuous learning and self-development, enabling me to provide an excellent customer shopping experience.
- Maintain my departments merchandising and readiness to serve customers. Back up the sales team for phone and store pickup.
- Perform other duties as assigned.

Summer League Swim Coach, West Hampton Swim Club, Tucker, Georgia

Summer League Swim Coach, May 2016 - August 2016

- Assist Head coach in creating thorough age-appropriate workouts focusing on technique endurance stroke development and drills
- Lead structured practices in weekday evenings during morning and afternoon in the summer

Referee, Triumph Youth Soccer Association & Chiefs FC, Tucker, Georgia

http://www.tysa.com/ & http://www.chiefsfc.org/

Referee, September 2011 - August 2015

- Ensure games are conducted in a safe and orderly manner, by controlling players, coaches, and parents as well as enforcing laws of the game
- Communicated with other officials quickly and efficiently to make decisions
- Report match results to regulating organizations in a timely manner

Lifeguard, Smoketree Pools, Tucker, GA

Lifeguard, May 2012 - October 2014

- Maintain continuous surveillance of people in swimming pools
- Supervise swimmers to ensure that they are swimming within the safety protocols
- Spot hazards or potential hazards and take measures to prevent accidents
- Perform pool chemical checks to ensure safety and hygiene